

SHAZIL MUHAMMED SHAFEEK

Devops Engineer

Address - Marathahalli, Bangalore

Mobile - +91 9562066323,

+91 7012020522

Email - shaazilmohd@gmail.com

PROFILE

Performance driven and dedicated Devops Engineer, possessing 6 plus years of extensive industry experience on Devops and Linux Administration. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Computer Science and Engineering from University of Calicut.

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/shazilmuham med-shafeek

SKILLS

- AWS
- Docker
- Ansible
- Puppet
- Linux
- Linode
- E2E Networks
- Jenkins
- Gitlab
- Github
- Apache
- Nginx
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Shell Scripting
- Nagios
- Zabbix
- IT Infrastructure management

EDUCATION

- B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (Calicut university)
- PLUS TWO
 (Kerala State Board)
- SSLC (Kerala State Board)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Devops Engineer

Razorpay, Bangalore (Jan 2022 - present)

• System Administrator

Intel Technologies, Bangalore (Dec 2020 - Dec 2021)

• Linux Administrator

IBM India pvt ltd, Bangalore (June 2019 - June 2020)

• Systems Engineer, IT Operations

QBurst Technologies, Kerala (Nov 2015 - Jan 2018)

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Razorpay:

- Manage deployment of frontend and backend applications on production (AWS, Linode), testing (AWS, Linode, E2E Network) and development (Onpremise) environments.
- Automate tasks using Ansible.
- Configure and manage Docker containers.
- Configure and manage Mysql, mongo databases.
- Configure and manage jenkins.
- Configure Apache, Nginx web server.
- Gitlab Administration.
- Manage Citrix Xenserver Hypervisor for the development environments.
- Provide support on Crate services CrateDB, Kafka, Dataware & Maxwell to get the transaction records.
- Provide support on debugging application level issues.

Intel Technologies:

- Install and configure Docker.
- Use Ansible for automating tasks.
- Install and configure Ubuntu, Centos, Redhat, Windows based on the development requirements.
- Install and configure blade servers Supermicro, intel and dell servers.
- Configure proxy for Lab network devices.
- Coordinate with IT Support team for Lab network Infrastructure requirements.
- Configure Proxmox VM tool, create cluster and configure VM's.
- Manage KVM devices.
- Provide support for network connectivity issues.

- Cyberoam
- Citrix Xencntre
- Proxmox
- Network Administration

KEY STRENGTHS AND PERSONAL QUALITIES

- Ability to assess problems and research solutions
- Flexibility
- Responsiveness
- Proactive
- Time management
- Interactive and a team player

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Date of Birth: 29th October 1991
- Sex & Status: Male & Married
- Nationality: INDIAN
- Languages Known: English, Malayalam, Tamil and Hindi

REFERENCES

- Lokesha HS

 (lokesha.hs@razorpay.com)
 Lead Devops Engineer
 (Razorpay)
 Mob: 9844808926
- Rashmi M A (rashmi.m.a@intel.com)
 Program Manager Mob: 9902016851
- Puneet Kittur (puneet_kittur@in.ibm.com)
 Delivery Operations Manager, IBM
- Arun S Raj (arunraj@qburst.com)
 Associate Architect, Devops (QBurst Technologies)
 Mob: 9995333287

Mob: 9611127003

 Sabeesh Thomas (sabeesh@qburst.com)
 Associate Manager (QBurst Technologies)
 Mob: 9535712352

IBM India pvt ltd:

- Monitoring the Customer Servers, Applications and environment.
- Performing first level problem determinations.
- Perform health checks on servers, monitoring backups and rerun if failed.
- Execute Scripts as per the schedule and manage time dependent and task dependent scripts.
- Attend Daily service reviews, change approval and walkthrough calls.
- Perform L1 troubleshooting, engage concerned teams and drive incidents to resolutions.

QBurst Technologies:

- Deploy and manage Docker containers.
- Manage AWS EC2 instances.
- Manage Cyberoam Firewall.
- Provide support for configuring Apache and Nginx web servers.
- Database administration on Mysql and PostgreSQL.
- Manage Linux, Windows and Mac systems.
- Provide Support for Hostingsource customer on Linux and Windows server issues.
- Administration of Antivirus Server and Clients by using Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Monitoring bandwidth usage and maintain reports.
- Provide support for backup/recovery and disaster recovery solutions.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Automate with ansible tool for upgrading java version and its dependency files on production environment.
- Configure Docker Server and local repository for development team.
- Configured Phabricator, Bugzilla and Redmine bug tracking tools.
- Configured Cyberoam Firewall.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- RHCE (Red Hat Certified Engineer)
- CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)
- MCSA (Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate)

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

SHAZIL MUHAMMED SHAFEEK